<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 5-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en"> &lt;p&gt; The indicator is based on the assessment of legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality using a questionnaire consisting of 45 binary “Yes / No” answer questions in four areas of law, drawn from the international legal and political framework on equality in particular, CEDAW and the Beijing Platform for Action &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The answers to the questions are coded with simple answers &quot;Yes / No&quot;, with &quot;1&quot; for &quot;Yes&quot; and &quot;0&quot; for &quot;No&quot;. Only for questions 1 and 2, they can be scored as &quot;N / A&quot;, in which case they are not included as part of the overall score calculation for area &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt; [2] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The scoring methodology is the unweighted average of the questions in each area of the law, calculated as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Where &lt;sub&gt; i &lt;/sub&gt; refers to the right area &lt;strong&gt; i &lt;/strong&gt;; m &lt;sub&gt; i &lt;/sub&gt; refers to the total number of questions in the area of the law &lt;strong&gt; i &lt;/strong&gt;; &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-3&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt; [3] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; q &lt;sub&gt; &lt;/sub&gt; 1 + ... + q &lt;sub&gt; mi &lt;/sub&gt; refers to the sum of coded questions in the legal and where q i area &lt;sub&gt; &lt;/sub&gt; = &quot;1&quot; if the answer is &quot;Yes&quot; eq &lt;sub&gt; i &lt;/sub&gt; = ”0” if the answer is “No”. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The results of the four areas are reported as a percentage panel (A &lt;sub&gt; &lt;/sub&gt; 1, A 2 &lt;sub&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;, &lt;sub&gt; The &lt;/sub&gt; 3, A 4 &lt;sub&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;). The score for each area (a number between 0 and 100) therefore represents the percentage of that country&apos;s achievements in that area, with 100 being best practices answered in all questions in the area. The choice to present all four scores in the area without additional aggregation is the result of adopting the stance that high values in one area in one country need not compensate in any way for the country with low values in some other area and that a comprehensive examination The value of these four numbers for each country is potentially more informative than trying to summarize all four numbers in a single index. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt; 2 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; For questions 1 and 2, the methodology does not give a positive or negative score to the existence or are subject to the existence of a Therefore, in countries where customary or personal law does not apply, these questions are classified as &quot;N / A&quot; and are not included as part of the overall score calculation for the &apos;comprehensive legal frameworks and public life&apos; area. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt; ↑ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-3&quot;&gt; 3 &lt;/sup&gt; a0d0d0n0d0n0d0n0d &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt; ↑ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;O indicador é baseado na avaliação de quadros legais que promovem, aplicam e monitoram a igualdade de género usando um questionário composto por 45 perguntas de resposta binária “Sim/Não” em quatro áreas do direito, extraídas do quadro jurídico e político internacional sobre igualdade de género, em particular, a CEDAW e o Plataforma de Acção de Pequim &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As respostas para as perguntas são codificadas com respostas simples &quot;Sim/Não&quot;, com &quot;1&quot; para &quot;Sim&quot; e &quot;0&quot; para &quot;Não&quot;. Apenas para as perguntas 1 e 2, elas podem ser pontuadas como &quot;N/A&quot;, caso em que não são incluídas como parte do cálculo geral da pontuação para a área&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A metodologia de pontuação é a média não ponderada das perguntas em cada área do direito, calculada da seguinte forma:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onde A&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt; se refere à área do direito &lt;strong&gt;i&lt;/strong&gt;; m&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt; refere-se ao número total de perguntas na área da lei &lt;strong&gt;i&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-3&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; q&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; + ... + q&lt;sub&gt;mi&lt;/sub&gt; refere-se à soma das perguntas codificadas na área jurídica e onde q&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt; = ”1” se a resposta for “Sim” e q&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt; = ”0” se a resposta for “Não”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Os resultados das quatro áreas são reportados em percentagens como um painel: (A&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;, A&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, A&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;, A&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;). A pontuação para cada área (um número entre 0 e 100) representa, portanto, a percentagem de realizações desse país nessa área, com 100 sendo as melhores práticas atendidas em todas as perguntas da área. A escolha de apresentar todas as quatro pontuações da área sem agregação adicional é o resultado da adopção da postura de que valores altos numa área em determinado país não precisam compensar de forma alguma o país com valores baixos em alguma outra área e que um exame abrangente do valor desses quatro números para cada país é potencialmente mais informativo do que tentar resumir todos os quatro números em um único índice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Para as perguntas 1 e 2, a metodologia não atribui uma pontuação (positiva ou negativa) à existência de direito consuetudinário ou pessoal, mas pontua se elas estão sujeitas aos princípios constitucionais de igualdade ou não discriminação. Portanto, em países onde o direito consuetudinário ou pessoal não se aplica, essas perguntas são classificadas como &quot;N/A&quot; e não são incluídas como parte do cálculo geral da pontuação para a área &apos;marcos legais abrangentes e vida pública&apos;. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;↑&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Se uma pergunta for codificada como &quot;N/A&quot;, ela não será contada no número total de perguntas em uma área da lei. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;↑&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
