<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for the indicator 5-1-1, translated into en</message>
	<data> &lt;p&gt; 5. Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 5.1 End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1&gt; 5.1.1 Whether or not legal frameworks exist to promote, apply and monitor equality and non-discrimination based on sex &lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt; 5.1.1 Legal frameworks to promote, apply and monitor equality and non-discrimination based on sex, whether existing or not. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 10/3/2020 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; No indicators related to0679c9a6a6d43z0 &lt;p&gt; Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Ângelo Tivane and Arnaldo Muthemba &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Planning and Cooperation Directorate &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Head of the Planning Department; Statistics technician &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; +258 828351430; +258 840560048; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; +258 826081976; +258 842268933 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Angelotivane2011@gmail.com&quot;&gt; Angelotivane2011@gmail.com &lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:muthembarnaldo@gmail.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; muthembarnaldo@gmail.com &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Angelotivane2011@gmail.com&quot;&gt; Angelotivane2011@gmail.com &lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:muthembarnaldo@gmail.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; muthembarnaldo@gmail.com &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The indicator measures the government&apos;s efforts to establish legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The indicator is based on an assessment of legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Percentage &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Administrative source. Ministry of Justice, Constitutional and Religious Affairs and the Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action surveyed the existing legislation on the matter and updates it annually, answered the questions and proceeds to the calculation according to international procedures. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; March 2020 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; April 2020 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Ministry of Justice, Constitutional and Religious Affairs and the Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Presidential Decree nº 9/2015, of 13 March, Resolution nº 18/2015, of 10 July; Ministerial Diploma 117/2015, of December 31; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The indicator is based on the use of the questionnaire composed of 45 “yes / no” answer questions in four areas of law: (i) Comprehensive legal frameworks and public life; (ii) violence against women; (iii) employment and economic benefits; and (iv) marriage and family. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The indicator is reliable, as the data are collected at source at national level and is internationally comparable. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The indicator is based on the assessment of legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality using a questionnaire consisting of 45 binary “Yes / No” answer questions in four areas of law, drawn from the international legal and political framework on equality in particular, CEDAW and the Beijing Platform for Action &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The answers to the questions are coded with simple answers &quot;Yes / No&quot;, with &quot;1&quot; for &quot;Yes&quot; and &quot;0&quot; for &quot;No&quot;. Only for questions 1 and 2, they can be scored as &quot;N / A&quot;, in which case they are not included as part of the overall score calculation for area &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt; [2] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The scoring methodology is the unweighted average of the questions in each area of the law, calculated as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Where &lt;sub&gt; i &lt;/sub&gt; refers to the right area &lt;strong&gt; i &lt;/strong&gt;; m &lt;sub&gt; i &lt;/sub&gt; refers to the total number of questions in the area of the law &lt;strong&gt; i &lt;/strong&gt;; &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-3&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt; [3] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; q &lt;sub&gt; &lt;/sub&gt; 1 + ... + q &lt;sub&gt; mi &lt;/sub&gt; refers to the sum of coded questions in the legal and where q i area &lt;sub&gt; &lt;/sub&gt; = &quot;1&quot; if the answer is &quot;Yes&quot; eq &lt;sub&gt; i &lt;/sub&gt; = ”0” if the answer is “No”. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The results of the four areas are reported as a percentage panel (A &lt;sub&gt; &lt;/sub&gt; 1, A 2 &lt;sub&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;, &lt;sub&gt; The &lt;/sub&gt; 3, A 4 &lt;sub&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;). The score for each area (a number between 0 and 100) therefore represents the percentage of that country&apos;s achievements in that area, with 100 being best practices answered in all questions in the area. The choice to present all four scores in the area without additional aggregation is the result of adopting the stance that high values in one area in one country need not compensate in any way for the country with low values in some other area and that a comprehensive examination The value of these four numbers for each country is potentially more informative than trying to summarize all four numbers in a single index. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt; 2 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; For questions 1 and 2, the methodology does not give a positive or negative score to the existence or are subject to the existence of a Therefore, in countries where customary or personal law does not apply, these questions are classified as &quot;N / A&quot; and are not included as part of the overall score calculation for the &apos;comprehensive legal frameworks and public life&apos; area. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt; ↑ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-3&quot;&gt; 3 &lt;/sup&gt; a0d0d0n0d0n0d0n0d &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt; ↑ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt; Validation is done by the collective by the national gender direction then by the technical and advisory council &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The method used is in accordance with international measurement standards of this indicator &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The data are analyzed by the Monitoring and Evaluation Division team, by the head of the Planning Department, by the Director of planning and cooperation, by the Technical Council and finally by the Advisory Council of the Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Working with gender focal points contributes to the quality of the answers given to the questions 45 questions that contribute to the calculation of the indicator &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action is organizing the statistical area to work in coordination with the National Statistics Institute (INE) to improve the quality of the entire process, from data collection to data publication. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The data is disaggregated into Four areas of law: (i) comprehensive legal frameworks and public life; (ii) violence against women; (iii) employment and economic benefits; and (iv) marriage and family. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; This indicator is global and can be compared with other countries. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; www.mgcas.mz.co &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
