<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_ASSURE field for indicator 5-2-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en"> &lt;p&gt; For data collection, the methodology of interviews was applied face to face with households, applying three types of questionnaires: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; • Household Questionnaire &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; • Women&apos;s Questionnaire &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; • Men&apos;s Questionnaire. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The questionnaires were based on the model used by the Demographic and Health surveys in their sixth phase. In addition to the main questions of the sixth phase IDS, some modifications were made to the questions and some specific questions were added in order to satisfy and answer the country&apos;s needs. It should be noted that these instruments have been properly pre-tested in urban and rural areas &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The sample design of IDS-2011 comprises a probabilistic, stratified and multi-stage sample, selected from the Data and Cartography of the III General Census of Population and Housing, carried out by INE in 2007. The sample allows to obtain accurate estimates at the level national, urban and rural, regional and provincial. The sample covers only the population residing in households. Households and respective members residing in collective residences, such as hotels, hospitals, military barracks, student homes, etc., and homeless people, which together make up 3.3% of the country&apos;s total population, were excluded from the sample. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;Para a recolha de dados, aplicou-se a metodologia de entrevistas frente a frente aos agregados familiares, aplicando-se três tipos de questionários: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Questionário de Agregados Familiares &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Questionário de Mulheres &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Questionário de Homens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Os questionários tiveram como base o modelo utilizado pelos inquéritos Demográficos e de Saúde na sua sexta fase. Além das perguntas principais do IDS da sexta fase, foram introduzidas algumas modificações nas perguntas e acrescentadas algumas questões específicas a fim de satisfazer e responder as necessidades do País. É de referir que estes instrumentos foram devidamente pré-testados em áreas urbanas e rurais&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O desenho da amostra do IDS-2011 compreende uma amostra probabilística, estratificada e multi-etápica, seleccionado a partir dos Dados e Cartografia do III Recenseamento Geral de População e Habitação, realizado pelo INE em 2007. A amostra permite obter estimativas precisas a nível nacional, urbano e rural, regional e provincial. A amostra abrange somente a população residente em agregados familiares. Foi excluída da amostra os agregados familiares e respectivos membros residentes em residências colectivas, como hotéis, hospitais, quartéis militares, lares de estudantes, etc., e os sem casa, os quais em conjunto perfazem 3.3% do total da população do pais.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
