<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 3-b-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en"> &lt;p&gt; Percentage of children aged 12-23 months who received specific vaccines at a certain time before the interview (according to the vaccination card or mother&apos;s statement). &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; You are considered to have taken all basic vaccines if your child has received at least: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; One dose of BCG vaccine (Bacillus Calmette Guérin), which protects against tuberculosis, &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Three doses of pentavalent vaccine, which protects against diphtheria, pertussis (whooping cough), tetanus, hepatitis B and Haemophilus influenza, &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Three doses of polio vaccine, &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; One dose of the measles vaccine, &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Three doses of the PCV vaccine, which protects against pneumonia. &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Sample: Children aged 12-23 months. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;Percentagem das crianças de 12-23 meses que receberam vacinas específicas a uma dada altura antes da entrevista (de acordo com o cartão de vacinas ou a declaração da mãe).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considera-se que tomou todas as vacinas básicas se a criança recebeu pelo menos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uma dose da vacina BCG (Bacilo Calmette Guérin), que protege contra a tuberculose,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Três doses da vacina pentavalente, que protege contra a difteria, coqueluche (tosse convulsa), tétano, hepatite B e Haemophilus influenza,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Três doses da vacina contra a poliomielite,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uma dose da vacina contra o sarampo,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Três doses da vacina PCV, que protege contra a pneumonia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Amostra: Crianças de 12-23 meses.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
