<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 6-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en"> &lt;p&gt; The Standard Model contains 32 questions divided into the four main components, namely: 1. Favorable environment; 2. Institutions and participation; 3. Management tools; and, 4. Financing. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ol&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Each question receives a score between 0 and 100, in intervals of 10, based on the following 6 main categories: &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ol&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Very low (0) &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Low (20) &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Mid-low (40) &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Mid-high (60) &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; High (80) &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Very high (100) &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Please note that guidelines are provided for each limit of each question, to ensure objective and comparable results. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ol&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; The unweighted average of the question scores in each of the four components is calculated to provide a score from 0 to 100 for each component. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; The component score is averaged (unweighted) to provide the indicator score, expressed as a percentage between 0 and 100. &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ol&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;O Modelo padrão contém 32 perguntas divididas nas quatro principais componentes, nomeadamente: 1. Ambiente favorável; 2. Instituições e participação; 3. Instrumentos de gestão; e, 4. Financiamento.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cada pergunta recebe uma pontuação entre 0 e 100, em intervalos de 10, com base nas 6 principais categorias a seguir:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Muito baixo (0)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Baixo (20)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Médio-baixo (40)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Médio-alto (60)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alto (80)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Muito alto (100)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observe que são fornecidas orientações para cada limite de cada pergunta, para garantir resultados objectivos e comparáveis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A média não ponderada das pontuações da pergunta em cada um dos quatro componentes é calculada para fornecer uma pontuação de 0 a 100 para cada componente.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A pontuação do componente é calculada como média (sem ponderação) para fornecer a pontuação do indicador, expressa como uma percentagem entre 0 e 100.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
