<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for the indicator 6-5-1, translated into en</message>
	<data> &lt;p&gt; 6 ENSURE THE AVAILABILITY AND SUSTAINABLE MANAGEMENT OF DRINKING WATER AND SANITATION FOR ALL &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 6.5 By 2030, implement integrated water resources management at all levels, including via cross-border cooperation, as appropriate &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 6.5.1 Degree of implementation of integrated water resources management (0-100) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Implementation of integrated water resources management (0-100) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 10/8/2020 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Not linked to other indicators &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; National Directorate of Water Resources Management &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Egídio Govate &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Planning Department &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Head of Department &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; +258 84 68 58 064 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:egovate@dngrh.gov.mz&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt; egovate@dngrh.gov.mz &lt;/u&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:egovate@gmail.com&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt; egovate@gmail.com &lt;/u&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The IWRM concept is measured in 4 main components: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ol&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Favorable environment: includes the policies, laws, plans and strategies that create the &quot;favorable environment&quot; for IWRM. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Institutions: includes the range and roles of political, social, economic and administrative institutions that support the implementation of IWRM. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Management Instruments: the tools and activities that allow decision-makers and users to make rational and informed choices between alternative actions. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Financing: Budget and financing made available and used for the development and management of water resources from various sources. &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;p&gt; Percentage &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Ministry of Public Works, Housing and Water Resources (National Directorate for Water Resources Management), administrative records. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The United Nations has created a standard data collection model for different actors in the integrated water resources management process. In order to be able to guarantee the collection of data at national level, the Ministry of Public Works, Housing and Water Resources holds a seminar in the second half of each year with the technical planning teams that enable the completion of the model. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; October 2021 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; December 2021 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Ministry of Public Works, Housing and Water Resources &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Ministry of Public Works, Housing and Water Resources - National Directorate of Water Resources Management &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; According to Ministerial Diploma 72/2012, the National Statistics Institute delegated powers of notation and calculation of statistical data to the Ministry of Public Works and Housing, through the Bakery and Cooperation Directorate, which has the following duties: (i) to prepare and coordinate the water and sanitation area planning process; (ii) preparing medium and long-term plans for the water sector and monitoring its implementation; (iii) monitor the execution of investment plans and propose corrective measures; and, (iv) to evaluate and monitor the activities of the area. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The indicator provides a direct measure of the progress of the implementation of integrated water resources management. The percentage score provides an easy and understandable way to measure progress towards the goal, with &apos;0&apos; interpreted as no IWRM implementation and &apos;100&apos; interpreted as IWRM being fully implemented. The indicator results can be classified similarly to the survey questions: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Degree of implementation = &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Very low (0-9,9) &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Low (10-29.9) &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Mid-low (30-49.9) &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Mid-high (50-69.9) &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; High (70-89.9) &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Very high (90-100) &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt; Consolidation is still necessary in relation to related basin committees as the management of basins / aquifers is still in the initial stage of implementation and operationalization. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The Standard Model contains 32 questions divided into the four main components, namely: 1. Favorable environment; 2. Institutions and participation; 3. Management tools; and, 4. Financing. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ol&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Each question receives a score between 0 and 100, in intervals of 10, based on the following 6 main categories: &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ol&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Very low (0) &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Low (20) &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Mid-low (40) &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Mid-high (60) &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; High (80) &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Very high (100) &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Please note that guidelines are provided for each limit of each question, to ensure objective and comparable results. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ol&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; The unweighted average of the question scores in each of the four components is calculated to provide a score from 0 to 100 for each component. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; The component score is averaged (unweighted) to provide the indicator score, expressed as a percentage between 0 and 100. &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;p&gt; Monitoring of the results of data compilation is carried out by technicians from the Ministry of Public Works, Housing and Water Resources &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; In the process of creating the Quality Management System at the level of the National Statistical System. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Meetings with the main players in the integrated water resources management process for data collection and analysis of its consistency. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The instruments for assessing the quality of statistical processes and products at the level of the National Statistical System are still being developed based on the 19 quality principles established by the United Nations Statistical Commission. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Data are made available annually and have no breakdown. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The calculation methodology that has been established internationally is used, so it is believed that the data are comparable. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 1. &lt;strong&gt; National Water Resources Plan (PNRH) 2020 &lt;/strong&gt; -2024, &lt;em&gt; Resolution Nr 11/2019, of 12 March; &lt;/em&gt; 2. &lt;strong&gt; Action Plan for the Implementation of Water Resources Development Goals &lt;/strong&gt; (PA-ODS RH) 2015-2030, &lt;em&gt; Resolution Nr.</data>
</root>
