<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for the indicator 8-7-1, translated into en</message>
	<data> &lt;p&gt; 8 PROMOTING INCLUSIVE AND SUSTAINABLE ECONOMIC GROWTH, FULL AND PRODUCTIVE JOBS AND DECENT WORK FOR ALL &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 8.7 Take immediate and effective measures to eradicate forced labor, end modern slavery and human trafficking, and ensure the prohibition and elimination of the worst forms of child labor, including recruitment and use of child soldiers, and by 2025 child labor in all its forms &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 8.7.1 Percentage and number of children from 5 to 17 years old performing child labor, by sex, age group &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Percentage and number of children from 5 to 17 years old performing child labor, by sex, age group &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 10/21/2020 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF STATISTICS &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Teixeira Mandlate, Maria Alfeu and João Mangue &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Directorate of Demographic, Vital and Social Statistics &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Technicians &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; +258 844386629; +258 823032619; +258 827679480 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; www.ine.gov.mz &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Teixeira.mandlate@ine.gov.mz&quot;&gt; Teixeira.mandlate@ine.gov.mz &lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:maria.alfeu@ine.gov.mz&quot;&gt; maria.alfeu@ine.gov.mz &lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:joao.mangue@ine.gov.mz&quot;&gt; joao.mangue@ine.gov.mz &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The number of children involved in child labor corresponds to the number of children reported in child labor during the reference period (usually in the week prior to the survey). The proportion of children in child labor is calculated as the number of children in child labor divided by the total number of children in the population. For the purposes of this indicator, children include all persons aged 5 to 17 years &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Percentage &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Household Surveys &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The recommended data source for calculating this indicator is the Family Budget Surveys. The data collection questionnaire is designed and subsequently tested in the field in the course of training the interviewers. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The IOF 2014/2015 is a probabilistic, stratified and multi-stage survey, designed according to a panel methodology based on households residing in private homes. In other words, each selected household (PA) was visited four times during the complete 12-month cycle, once only in each quarter, in order to reflect seasonality during the year. The visit to each household lasted 7 continuous days. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Data collection took place over 12 months starting on August 7, 2014 and ending on August 15, 2015 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 2020 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 2021 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; INE &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; INE &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Law 7/96 of 5 July &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Many children in the world remain trapped in child labor, compromising their individual future and our collective future. According to the most recent global ILO estimates, about 152 million children worldwide - 64 million girls and 88 million boys - are children, representing almost 10% of the child population. These evident numbers emphasize the need for accelerated progress against child labor by 2025 - the target date for ending child labor in all its forms and the need for child labor statistics to monitor and guide efforts in this direction. Reliable, comprehensive and timely data on the nature and extent of child labor provide a basis for determining priorities for global national action against child labor. Statistical information on child labor and, more broadly, on all working children, also provides a basis for raising public awareness of the situation of working children and for the development of appropriate regulatory frameworks and policies &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Although the concept of child labor includes work in activities of a dangerous nature, to ensure comparability of estimates over time and to minimize data quality problems, work beyond age-specific time limits is used as a proxy for dangerous work for the purpose of reporting indicator 8.7.1. Additional methodological work is needed to validate issues specifically designed to identify children in dangerous working conditions. Likewise, while the worst forms of child labor that are not dangerous are also part of the concept of child labor more broadly, data on the worst forms of child labor are currently not captured in surveys of regular households due to difficulties in measuring it accurately and reliably &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The proportion of children aged 5 to 14 years is calculated by dividing the number of children aged 5 to 14 years registered in child labor during the week prior to the survey, by the total number of children aged 5 to 14 years in the population, multiplied by 100 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The fieldwork had the supervision and quality control by the technicians of INE Central as well as the Provincial Delegations. In addition, during the data collection, a strict control was established at the level of each team over the collection process, by detecting errors by the critics in the field, which allowed for immediate correction even on the ground. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; At the level of central coordination, the data critics made a further review of the base data and the problems encountered were reported to the respective teams for correction. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Interactive and batch processing of information also allowed, at central level, the periodic obtaining of partial results, for analysis of the data collected until a given moment, through the production of tables for monitoring and quality control. The results of these tabulations were reported in feedback to the inquirers, ensuring the quality of the data. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; For the collection of IOF data, 5 types of questionnaires were used: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; 1. Questionnaire on the General Characteristics of the Household; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; 2. Questionnaire on Household Daily Expenses; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; 3. Expenses and Revenue Questionnaire (annual and monthly); &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; 4. Community Questionnaire (completed by the Controller). The latter was used only in rural areas; e &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; 5. Questionnaire for people aged 5 and over (employment). In addition, a module on tourist activity in Mozambique has been included. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; In practical terms, two modalities of data collection were used: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Electronics (Tablets) for the 5 types of Questionnaires, &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; On paper for Daily Expenses and Monthly and Annual Expenses and Income Questionnaires to ensure greater reliability given its complexity of collection. The collection of data in a household was made through 3 visits to the accommodation units for 7 continuous days, respecting the following distribution: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; On the day of the first visit, the inquirer filled out the Household General Characteristics Questionnaire and part of the Daily Expenses Questionnaire (expenses, self-consumption and income in kind corresponding to the previous day). At this stage, the inquirer also completed the module on tourism. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; On the second visit, (three days after the first) the Inquirer collected monthly and annual expenses and completed the Household Daily Expenditure Questionnaire for the last 3 days. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; On the third visit (three days after the second) the Inquirer collected income and transfers and filled out the Household Daily Expenses Questionnaire in the last 3 days. The surveyors were regularly asked to, after collecting the data in the field using the Questionnaire on paper or via Tablet, be sent to the respective Controller, who in turn compiled all the data and sent it via the internet to INE Central for the Informatics and Criticism-Coding and Typing sector. The Critics and Coding Team performed a quality analysis and assigned codes to open questions - Questionnaire on paper. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Still in development and to be approved by the quality management instrument &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; For the collection of data, the methodology of interviews was applied face to face to the households filling out the Bulletin of Households and Bulletin of collective accommodations. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Still in development and for approval of the instrument for quality assessment &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Information is made available every 5 years and is disaggregated by sex, age groups, rural and urban area of residence, province and country &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The results of the Family Budget Survey (IOF) allow comparability because the conception of measuring variables derives from the recommendations from the International Conference of Labor Statistics (CIET) as well as from the ILO. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; National Statistics Institute (INE), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.misau.gov.mz&quot;&gt; www.misau.gov.mz &lt;/a&gt;; Ministry of Labor, Employment and Social Security (MITESS), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mitess.gov.mz&quot;&gt; www.mitess.gov.mz &lt;/a&gt;; &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
