<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 8-7-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en"> &lt;p&gt; Many children in the world remain trapped in child labor, compromising their individual future and our collective future. According to the most recent global ILO estimates, about 152 million children worldwide - 64 million girls and 88 million boys - are children, representing almost 10% of the child population. These evident numbers emphasize the need for accelerated progress against child labor by 2025 - the target date for ending child labor in all its forms and the need for child labor statistics to monitor and guide efforts in this direction. Reliable, comprehensive and timely data on the nature and extent of child labor provide a basis for determining priorities for global national action against child labor. Statistical information on child labor and, more broadly, on all working children, also provides a basis for raising public awareness of the situation of working children and for the development of appropriate regulatory frameworks and policies &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;Muitas crianças no mundo permanecem presas ao trabalho infantil, comprometendo seu futuro individual e nosso futuro colectivo. De acordo com as estimativas globais mais recentes da OIT, cerca de 152 milhões de crianças em todo o mundo - 64 milhões de meninas e 88 milhões de meninos - são crianças, representando quase 10% da população infantil. Esses números evidentes enfatizam a necessidade de progresso acelerado contra o trabalho infantil até 2025 – a data da Meta para o término do trabalho infantil em todas as suas formas e a necessidade de estatísticas do trabalho infantil para monitorar e orientar os esforços nesse sentido. Dados fiáveis, abrangentes e oportunos sobre a natureza e extensão do trabalho infantil fornecem uma base para determinar as prioridades da acção global nacional contra o trabalho infantil. As informações estatísticas sobre trabalho infantil e, mais amplamente, sobre todas as crianças que trabalham, também fornecem uma base para aumentar a conscientização do público sobre a situação das crianças que trabalham e para o desenvolvimento de quadros e políticas regulatórias apropriadas&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
