<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 7-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en"> &lt;p&gt; The recommended data source to calculate this indicator is the Census and Household Surveys. The data collection questionnaire is designed and subsequently tested in the field in the course of training the interviewers. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; For data collection, we applied the methodology of interviews face to face with households, where respondents were asked if the house has: flush toilets inside the house, flush toilet outside the home, toilet without flush toilet, latrine improved, improved traditional latrine. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The fieldwork lasted 15 days for the case of the Censuses and the Surveys depending on the type and purpose of the Survey. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Cases of non-response, after all efforts to obtain funds are exhausted, are treated as unknown cases. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;A fonte de dados recomendada para calcular este indicador s&amp;#xE3;o os Censos e Inqu&amp;#xE9;ritos aos Agregados Familiares. O question&amp;#xE1;rio da recolha de dados &amp;#xE9; desenhado e posteriormente testado no campo no decurso do treinamento dos entrevistadores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para a recolha de dados, aplicou-se a metodologia de entrevistas frente a frente aos agregados familiares onde perguntou-se aos inquiridos se a casa tem: retretes com autoclismo dentre de casa, retrete com autoclismo fora de casa, retrete sem autoclismo, latrina melhorada, latrina tradicional melhorada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O trabalho de campo teve a dura&amp;#xE7;&amp;#xE3;o de 15 dias para caso dos Censos e nos Inqu&amp;#xE9;ritos dependendo do tipo e objectivo do Inqu&amp;#xE9;rito.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Casos de n&amp;#xE3;o resposta, apos esgotadas todas as dilig&amp;#xEA;ncias para capta&amp;#xE7;&amp;#xE3;o, s&amp;#xE3;o tratados como casos desconhecidos.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
