<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 3-7-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en"> &lt;p&gt; Differences in the design and implementation of the survey, as well as differences in the way the questionnaires are formulated and administered, can affect the comparability of the data. The most common differences are related to the variety of contraceptive methods included and the characteristics (age, sex, marital status or union) of the people for whom the prevalence of contraceptives is estimated (base population). The timeframe used to assess the prevalence of contraceptives can also vary. In most surveys, there is no definition of what is meant by &quot;currently using&quot; a contraceptive method. In some surveys, the lack of probing questions, asked to ensure that the respondent understands the meaning of different contraceptive methods, may result in an underestimation of the prevalence of contraceptives, particularly in traditional methods. Sample variability can also be a problem, especially when the prevalence of contraceptives is measured for a specific subgroup (according to the method, age group, education level, place of residence, etc.) or when analyzing trends over time . When data on women aged 15 to 49 are not available, information is reported for women who are married or in union. Illustrations of grassroots populations that are sometimes presented are: married or married women aged 15 to 44, sexually active women (regardless of marital status) or married women. The notes in the data set indicate any differences between the data presented and the standard definitions of contraceptive prevalence or unmet need for family planning or where the data belong to populations that are not representative of women of reproductive age. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;Diferenças no design e implementação da pesquisa, bem como diferenças na forma como os questionários são formulados e administrados, podem afectar a comparabilidade dos dados. As diferenças mais comuns estão relacionadas com a variedade de métodos contraceptivos incluídos e às características (idade, sexo, estado civil ou união) das pessoas para as quais a prevalência de contraceptivos é estimada (população base). O prazo usado para avaliar a prevalência de contraceptivos também pode variar. Na maioria das pesquisas, não há definição do que se entende por &quot;actualmente usando&quot; um método contraceptivo. Em algumas pesquisas, a falta de perguntas de sondagem, solicitadas para garantir que o entrevistado entenda o significado dos diferentes métodos contraceptivos, pode resultar em uma subestimação da prevalência de contraceptivos, em particular nos métodos tradicionais. A variabilidade da amostra também pode ser um problema, especialmente quando a prevalência de contraceptivos é medida para um subgrupo específico (de acordo com o método, faixa etária, nível de escolaridade, local de residência etc.) ou ao analisar tendências ao longo do tempo. Quando os dados sobre mulheres de 15 a 49 anos não estão disponíveis, são reportadas informações para mulheres casadas ou em união. Ilustrações de populações de base que às vezes são apresentadas são: mulheres casadas ou em união de 15 a 44 anos, mulheres sexualmente activas (independentemente do estado civil) ou mulheres casadas. As notas no conjunto de dados indicam quaisquer diferenças entre os dados apresentados e as definições padrão de prevalência contraceptiva ou necessidade não atendida de planeamento familiar ou onde os dados pertencem a populações que não são representativas de mulheres em idade reprodutiva.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
