<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 1-2-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en"> &lt;p&gt; For the analysis of multidimensional poverty in Mozambique, the methodology &lt;em&gt; Alkire-Foster &lt;/em&gt; was used. This methodology allows the aggregation of dimensions and deprivation indicators. Our assessment was based on 17 indicators. As binary indicators, they can assume two values, 0 if the household is “non-private” and 1 if it is “private” for that indicator. Weights are assigned to dimensions and indicators. Subsequently, the limit (cutoff) of 40% of the heavy indicators was defined. Finally, private households at least 40% of private indicators were considered poor, and private households at less than 40% were considered non-poor. To calculate the Multidimensional Poverty Index of &lt;em&gt; Alkire-Foster &lt;/em&gt; we use the following formula: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Where: &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;Para a an&amp;#xE1;lise da pobreza multidimensional em Mo&amp;#xE7;ambique utilizou-se a metodologia &lt;em&gt;Alkire-Foster&lt;/em&gt;. Esta metodologia permite a agrega&amp;#xE7;&amp;#xE3;o de dimens&amp;#xF5;es e indicadores de priva&amp;#xE7;&amp;#xE3;o. A nossa avalia&amp;#xE7;&amp;#xE3;o foi com base em 17 indicadores. Sendo os indicadores bin&amp;#xE1;rios, podem assumir dois valores, 0 se o agregado familiar for &amp;#x201C;n&amp;#xE3;o privado&amp;#x201D; e 1 se for &amp;#x201C;privado&amp;#x201D; desse indicador. Atribui-se pesos as dimens&amp;#xF5;es e aos indicadores. Posteriormente, definiu-se o limite (cutoff) de 40% dos indicadores pesados. Por fim os agregados familiares privados pelo menos 40% dos indicadores privados foram considerados pobres, e os privados em menos de 40% foram considerados como n&amp;#xE3;o pobres. Para o c&amp;#xE1;lculo do &amp;#xCD;ndice de &amp;#xCD;ndice de Pobreza Multidimensional de &lt;em&gt;Alkire-Foster&lt;/em&gt; utilizamos a seguinte formula:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onde: &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
