<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for the indicator 1-2-2, translated into en</message>
	<data> &lt;p&gt; 1 ERADICATE POVERTY IN ALL ITS FORMS, EVERYWHERE &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 1.2. By 2030, reduce at least half the proportion of men, women and children, of all ages, living in poverty, in all its dimensions, according to national definitions. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 1.2.2 Percentage of men, women and children of all ages, living in poverty, in all its dimensions, according to national definitions &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Men, women and children of all ages, living in poverty, in all its dimensions, according to national definitions &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 9/10/2020 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Ministry of Economy and Finance (MEF) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; José Domingos Madeira Cardoso &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; National Directorate for Economic Policies and Development &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Senior Technician N1 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; +258 84 229 5957 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jsm.cardoso7@gmail.com&quot;&gt; jsm.cardoso7@gmail.com &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It is the percentage of households that are private in at least 40% of the 17 well-being indicators defined for Mozambique. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Percentage &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Ministry of Economy and Finance, Poverty and Welfare in Mozambique, Fourth national assessment according to IOF 2014/2015. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 1st semester of 2021 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; December 2021 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; National Institute of Statistics (INE) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Ministry of Economy and Finance (MEF) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; By joint order number &lt;strong&gt; 112 / DEAE-MF / 2012 of 8 June &lt;/strong&gt;, the National Statistics Institute delegated powers of notation and clearance of statistical data from administrative acts and inquiries to the Ministry of Finance through the Directorate of Studies and Economic Analysis . &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; This indicator shows the percentage of poor people, that is, private in at least 40% of the weighted indicators defined in Mozambique. For example, 53.3% of people in Mozambique are private in more than 40% of the weighted indicators. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The multidimensional poverty assessment can be influenced by the weighting of the indicators and, or the definition of the limit (cutoff). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; For the analysis of multidimensional poverty in Mozambique, the methodology &lt;em&gt; Alkire-Foster &lt;/em&gt; was used. This methodology allows the aggregation of dimensions and deprivation indicators. Our assessment was based on 17 indicators. As binary indicators, they can assume two values, 0 if the household is “non-private” and 1 if it is “private” for that indicator. Weights are assigned to dimensions and indicators. Subsequently, the limit (cutoff) of 40% of the heavy indicators was defined. Finally, private households at least 40% of private indicators were considered poor, and private households at less than 40% were considered non-poor. To calculate the Multidimensional Poverty Index of &lt;em&gt; Alkire-Foster &lt;/em&gt; we use the following formula: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Where: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 1. The data used are reliable at national, rural, urban and provincial levels; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; 2. Internal discussion at the level of the National Directorate for Economic Policy and Development, the Ministry of Economy and Finance, at the level of the Government, discussion with cooperation partners and civil society. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; In the process of creating the Quality Management System at the level of the National Statistical System. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; There is a team composed of the Ministry of Economy and Finance, the National Institute of Statistics and the World Bank that collaborates from the moment of the formulation of IOF surveys, data collection, and dissemination of results. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The instruments for assessing the quality of statistical processes and products at the level of the National Statistical System are still being developed based on the 19 quality principles established by the United Nations Statistical Commission. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Data available every 6 years, disaggregated by area of residence (rural and urban), sex, age group and &lt;em&gt; status &lt;/em&gt; (type) of occupation. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It is possible to make a comparison considering the Global MPI, but some need to be done in terms of weights and indicators and dimensions. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; DEEF (2016). Poverty and Well-Being in Mozambique: Fourth National Assessment. Maputo: Ministry of Economy and Finance. Available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wider.unu.edu/sites/default/files/Final_QUARTA%20AVALIA%C3%87AO%20NACIONAL%20DA%20POBREZA_2016-10-26_2.pdf&quot;&gt; https://www.wider.unu.edu/sites/default/files/Final_QUARTA%20AVALIA%C3%87AO%20NACIONAL%20DA%20POBREZA_2016-10-26_2.pdf &lt;/a&gt;; &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; INE (2015). Final Report of the Family Budget Survey - IOF 2014/15. Maputo: National Statistics Institute; available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ine.gov.mz/operacoes-estatisticas/inqueritos/inquerito-sobre-orcamento-familiar/relatorio-final-do-inquerito-ao-orcamento-familiar-iof-2014-15&quot;&gt; http://www.ine.gov.mz/operacoes-estatisticas/inqueritos/inquerito-sobre-orcamento-familiar/relatorio-final-do-inquerito-ao-orcamento-familiar-iof-2014-15 &lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;</data>
</root>
