<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DOC_METHOD field for indicator 8-6-1, translated into en</message>
	<data> &lt;p&gt; For the collection of IOF data, 5 types of questionnaires were used: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; 1. Questionnaire on the General Characteristics of the Household; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; 2. Questionnaire on Household Daily Expenses; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; 3. Expenses and Revenue Questionnaire (annual and monthly); &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; 4. Community Questionnaire (completed by the Controller). The latter was used only in rural areas; e &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; 5. Questionnaire for people aged 5 and over (employment). In addition, a module on tourist activity in Mozambique has been included. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; In practical terms, two modalities of data collection were used: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Electronics (Tablets) for the 5 types of Questionnaires, &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; On paper for Daily Expenses and Monthly and Annual Expenses and Income Questionnaires to ensure greater reliability given its complexity of collection. The collection of data in a household was made through 3 visits to the accommodation units for 7 continuous days, respecting the following distribution: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; On the day of the first visit, the inquirer filled out the Household General Characteristics Questionnaire and part of the Daily Expenses Questionnaire (expenses, self-consumption and income in kind corresponding to the previous day). At this stage, the inquirer also completed the module on tourism. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; On the second visit, (three days after the first) the Inquirer collected monthly and annual expenses and completed the Household Daily Expenditure Questionnaire for the last 3 days. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; On the third visit (three days after the second) the Inquirer collected income and transfers and filled out the Household Daily Expenses Questionnaire in the last 3 days. The surveyors were regularly asked to, after collecting the data in the field using the Questionnaire on paper or via Tablet, be sent to the respective Controller, who in turn compiled all the data and sent it via the internet to INE Central for the Informatics and Criticism-Coding and Typing sector. The Critics and Coding Team performed a quality analysis and assigned codes to open questions - Questionnaire on paper. &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
