<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 2-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en"> &lt;p&gt; The recommended data sources for calculating this indicator are household surveys (IOF and IDS) with national representation that constitute the data source. In either case, the child&apos;s height and weight should be measured following the recommended standard measurement techniques (WHO 2008). &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The questionnaire for the collection of data from the Demographic and Health Survey was designed and subsequently tested in the field during the training of the interviewers. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; For data collection, the methodology of interviews was applied face to face to the households, applying three types of questionnaires: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; • Household Questionnaire &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; • Women&apos;s Questionnaire &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; • Men&apos;s Questionnaire. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The Sample Design &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The Demographic and Health Survey comprises a probabilistic, stratified and multi-stage sample, selected from the Data and Cartography of the III General Census of Population and Housing, carried out by INE in 2007. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The data collection lasted for five months starting in June 2011, ending in November 2011. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Response rate &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Of the 13.964 households interviewed in the survey, a total of 13.871 eligible women were identified. Interviews were conducted with 13,718 of these women, which resulted in a response rate of 99%. Introduction • 13 In one third of the IDS household sample, interviews were also conducted with all eligible men found. Thus, of the 4,130 eligible men identified in the subsample of households selected for the men survey, 4,027 were successfully interviewed, giving a response rate of 98% &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;As fontes de dados recomendadas para calcular este indicador são os inquéritos aos agregados familiares (IOF e IDS) com representação nacional constituem a fonte de dados. Em qualquer dos casos, a altura e peso da criança devem ser medidos seguindo as técnicas de medição padrão recomendadas (OMS 2008).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O questionário da recolha de dados do Inquérito Demográfico e de Saúde foi desenhado e posteriormente testado no campo no decurso do treinamento dos entrevistadores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para a recolha de dados, aplicou-se a metodologia de entrevistas frente a frente aos agregados familiares aplicando-se três tipos de questionários: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Questionário de Agregados Familiares &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Questionário de Mulheres &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Questionário de Homens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O Desenho da Amostra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O Inquérito Demográfico e de Saúde compreende uma amostra probabilística, estratificada e multi-etápica, seleccionado a partir dos Dados e Cartografia do III Recenseamento Geral de População e Habitação, realizado pelo INE em 2007. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recolha de dados teve duração de cinco meses com início em Junho de 2011, tendo terminado em Novembro de 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taxa de resposta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dos 13,964 agregados entrevistados no inquérito foi identificado um total de 13,871 mulheres elegíveis. Foram feitas entrevistas a 13,718 destas mulheres, o que resultou numa taxa de resposta de 99%. Introdução • 13 Em um terço da amostra de agregados familiares do IDS, eram também feitas entrevistas a todos os homens elegíveis encontrados. Assim, dos 4,130 homens elegíveis identificados na subamostra de agregados familiares seleccionados para o inquérito de homens, foram entrevistados 4,027 com sucesso, dando uma taxa de respostas de 98%&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
