<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 3-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en"> &lt;p&gt; Tobacco use is a major contributor to disease and death from noncommunicable diseases (NCDs). There is no proven level of safety in the use of tobacco or passive exposure to smoke. All daily and non-daily tobacco users are at risk for a variety of poor health outcomes throughout their lives, including NCDs. Reducing the prevalence of current tobacco use will make a major contribution to reducing premature mortality from NCDs (target 3.4). &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; In addition to contributing to a detailed knowledge of the frequency of exposure to the main risk factors for NCDs in Mozambique, the information produced should allow to quantify the variation in these exposures in the last decade, through comparison with that observed in the first STEPS study, carried out in 2005. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The results obtained in this study, allow a better knowledge of the Mozambican reality in relation to exposures associated with DNT, with potential interest for health planning, constituting itself as a baseline to evaluate the evolution of these risk factors with based on STEPS studies to be carried out in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;O uso do tabaco é um dos principais contribuintes para doenças e morte por doenças não transmissíveis (DNTs). Não existe um nível comprovado de segurança no uso do tabaco ou na exposição passiva ao fumo. Todos os usuários diários e não diários de tabaco correm o risco de uma variedade de maus resultados de saúde ao longo da vida, incluindo as DNTs. Reduzir a prevalência do uso actual de tabaco dará uma grande contribuição para reduzir a mortalidade prematura por DNTs (meta 3.4).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para além de contribuir para um conhecimento detalhado da frequência de exposição aos principais fatores de risco para DNT em Moçambique, a informação produzida deverá permitir quantificar a variação nestas exposições na última década, através da comparação com o observado no primeiro estudo STEPS, efetuado em 2005.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Os resultados obtidos neste estudo, permitem um melhor conhecimento da realidade moçambicana em relação a exposições que se associam a DNT, com potencial interesse para o planeamento em saúde, constituindo-se como uma linha de base para avaliar a evolução destes fatores de risco com base em estudos STEPS a realizar no futuro.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
