<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 4-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en"> &lt;p&gt; 4: Guarantee Access to Inclusive, Quality and Equitable Education and, Promote Lifelong Learning Opportunities for All. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 4.4 By 2030, substantially increase the number of young people and adults who have relevant skills, including technical and professional skills, for employment, decent work and entrepreneurship. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 4.4.1 Percentage of young people and adults with skills in information and communication technology (ICT), by type of skill. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Percentage of young people and adults with skills in information and communication technology (ICT), by type of skill. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 10/8/2020 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Ministry of Science and Technology, Higher Education and Professional Technician (MCTESTP) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Tomé Lucas Wilson, Innocence Pale &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Directorate of Planning, Studies and Cooperation &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Head of the Planning and Monitoring Department and statistical technique &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; +258849136315, 847093829/827111410 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:tome.wilson@mctestp.gov.mz&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt; tome.wilson@mctestp.gov.mz &lt;/u&gt; &lt;/a&gt;, inocencia.phale@mctestp.gov.mz a0f559170 &lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:toluwil@gmail.com&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt; toluwil@gmail.com &lt;/u&gt; &lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:inocencia.pale@gmail.com&quot;&gt; innencia. &lt;p&gt; Percentage of young people (15 to 24 years old) and adults (aged 15 years and over) who performed certain computer activities in a certain period of time. Computer-related activities to measure ICT skills include: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; • Copy or move a file &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; • Use of copy and paste tools to duplicate or move information within the same document; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; • Sending e-mail with file attachments (e.g. photo, video); &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; • Use of basic arithmetic formula in a spreadsheet; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; • Connection and installation of new devices (e.g. modem, camera, printer); &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; • Find, download, install and configure software; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; • Creation of electronic presentations with presentation software (including text, images, sound, video or graphics); &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; • Transferring files between a computer and other devices; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; • Write a computer program using a specialized programming language. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Percentage &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Ministry of Science and Technology, Higher Education and Professional Technician (MCTESTP), Administrative data. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The data for the determination of this indicator are obtained through administrative surveys carried out by the National Institute of Electronic Government in the scope of the Training of Young People, Women, Officials and State Agents. Data is collected at the provincial digital resource centers and some at the ICT training centers. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; March of each year &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; December each year &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Ministry of Science and Technology, Higher Education and Professional Technician through the National Institute of Electronic Government. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Ministry of Science and Technology, Higher Education and Professional Technician through the National Institute of Electronic Government. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The Ministry and delegated organ of Statistics Portugal. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Produces statistics from the Science and Technology, Higher Education and Professional Technical Sector according to the joint order of December 2002, Bulletin of the Republic no &lt;sup&gt; o &lt;/sup&gt; 10, Series, of March 5, 2003. a0679c9a6a6d43 &lt;p&gt; This indicator links the use and impact of ICT and helps to measure and track the level of proficiency of users. A high value indicates that a large portion of the reference population has ICT skills. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The data collected to calculate the indicator do not capture information from private training centers that teach courses in the areas of ICT and are not disaggregated by type of skill. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; This indicator is obtained by the ratio between the number of young people and adults who have ICT skills and the total population resident in the country, multiplied by 100%. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The results of this operation are analyzed by the department of studies and statistics and then presented to the technical and advisory councils of the ministry for the purposes of assessment and final validation. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; To produce this indicator, methodological guidelines are used, which are included in the globally available metadata, the difference is in the fact that globally they use the type of specific skills while at the national level they apply all kinds of skills. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; In process the creation of the management system at the level of the national statistical system, however at the level of the ministry there is a department to manage the quality of statistical products: &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ol&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Collection and made through administrative acts. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; After collection, the studies and statistics department checks the quality of the entire process. &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;p&gt; To guarantee the quality required in the Statistics production process, the sector uses all correlated administrative information sources, in order to complement, validate and measure the information obtained. Also during the process of analysis and establishment of the data values, the sources of origin of the basic information are questioned whenever there are doubts or anomalous variations in the results obtained. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The instruments for assessing the quality of statistical processes and products at the level of the national statistical system are being developed based on the 19 quality principles established by the united nations statistics commission. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The data for this indicator are available annually and are not broken down by type of skill. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The determination of this indicator differs from the international one in that it relates people with ICT skills and the total population residing in the country and not a specific age group. The other aspect refers to the data source, for this indicator the data source used for the calculation is administrative and not survey. The calculation is not done by type of skill considers all skills. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Annual Balance of Activities of the CTESTP Sector. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;4: Garantir o Acesso a Educação Inclusiva, de Qualidade e Equitativa e, Promover Oportunidades de Aprendizagem ao Longo da Vida para Todos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4.4 Até 2030, aumentar substancialmente o número de jovens e adultos que tenham habilidades relevantes, inclusive competências técnicas e profissionais, para emprego, trabalho decente e empreendedorismo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4.4.1 Percentagem de jovens e adultos com habilidade em tecnologia de informação e comunicação (TIC), por tipo de habilidade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Percentagem de jovens e adultos com habilidade em tecnologia de informação e comunicação (TIC), por tipo de habilidade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;08/10/2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ministério da Ciência e Tecnologia, Ensino Superior e Técnico Profissional (MCTESTP)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tomé Lucas Wilson, Inocência Pale&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Direcção de Planificação, Estudos e Cooperação&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chefe do Departamento de Planificação e Monitoria e técnica de estatística&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;+258849136315, 847093829/827111410&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:tome.wilson@mctestp.gov.mz&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;tome.wilson@mctestp.gov.mz&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, inocencia.phale@mctestp.gov.mz&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:toluwil@gmail.com&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;toluwil@gmail.com&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:inocencia.pale@gmail.com&quot;&gt;inocencia.pale@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Percentagem de jovens (de 15 a 24 anos) e adultos (com idade igual ou superior a 15 anos) que realizaram determinadas actividades informáticas em um determinado período de tempo. Actividades relacionadas com a informática para medir habilidades em TIC incluem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Copiar ou mover um ficheiro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Uso de ferramentas de copiar e colar para duplicar ou mover informação dentro do mesmo documento;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Envio de correio electrónico com anexo de ficheiros (e.g. fotografia, vídeo);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Uso de fórmula básica de aritmética numa folha de calculo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Ligação e instalação de novos dispositivos (e.g. modem, câmera, impressora);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Encontrar, baixar, instalar e configurar software;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Criação de apresentações electrónicas com um software de apresentação (incluindo textos, imagens, som, vídeo ou gráfico);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Transferência de ficheiros entre um computador e outros dispositivos;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Escrever um programa de computador usando uma linguagem especializada de programação.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Percentagem&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ministério da Ciência e Tecnologia, Ensino Superior e Técnico Profissional (MCTESTP), Dados administrativos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Os dados para a determinação deste este indicador são obtidos através de levantamentos administrativos realizados pelo Instituto Nacional de Governo Electrónico no âmbito da Formação de Jovens, mulheres, funcionários e agentes do Estado. Os dados são coletados nos centros de recursos digitais provinciais e em alguns nos centros de formação em TIC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Março de cada ano&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dezembro de cada ano &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ministério da Ciência e Tecnologia, Ensino Superior e Técnico Profissional através da Instituto Nacional de Governo Electrónico.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ministério da Ciência e Tecnologia, Ensino Superior e Técnico Profissional através da Instituto Nacional de Governo Electrónico.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;O Ministério e órgão delegado do INE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Produz estatísticas do Sector de Ciência e Tecnologia, Ensino Superior e Técnico Profissional de acordo com o despacho conjunto, de Dezembro de 2002, Boletim da Republica n&lt;sup&gt;o&lt;/sup&gt; 10, I Serie, de 05 de Marco de 2003.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Este indicador faz a ligação entre o uso e o impacto das TIC e ajuda a medir e rastrear o nível de proficiência dos usuários. Um valor alto indica que uma grande parcela da população de referência possui habilidades em TIC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Os Dados coletados para cálculo do indicador não captam informação dos centros de formação privados que ministram cursos nas áreas das TICs e nao estao desagregados por tipo de habilidade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Este indicador obtém-se pela razão entre o número de jovens e adultos que possuem habilidades em TIC e a população total residente no país, multiplicado por 100%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Os resultados desta operacao, sao analisados pelo departamento de estudos e estatisticas e em seguida apresentados nos conselhos tecnico e consultivo do ministério para efeitos apreciação e validação final.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Para producao deste indicador, sao utilizadas orientacoes metodologicas que constam nos metadados disponiveis globalmente, a diferenca esta no facto de globalmente usarem o tipo de habilidades especificas enquanto que anivel nacional aplicam se todo tipo de habilidades. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Em processo a criação do sistema de gestão a nível do sistema estatístico nacional, no entanto ao nível do ministerio existe um departamento de gere a qualidade dos produtos estatísticos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recolha e feita atraves de actos administrativos.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Depois da recolha o departamento de estudos e estatistica faz a verificacao da qualidade em todo processo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Para garantir a qualidade requerida no Processo de produção das estatísticas, o sector utiliza todas as fontes de informação administrativas correlacionadas, no sentido de complementar, validar e aferir a informação obtida. Igualmente no decorrer do processo de análise e estabelecimento dos dados valores, as fontes de origem da informação de base são questionadas sempre que existirem dúvidas ou variações anómalas nos resultados obtidos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Os instrumentos para avaliação da qualidade dos processos e produtos estatísticos a a nivel do sistema estatistico Nacional estão a ser desenvolvidos com base nos 19 principios de qualidade estatelecidos pela comissão de estatísticas das nações unidas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Os dados deste indicador são disponibilizados anualmente e não estão desagregados por tipo de habilidade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A determinação deste indicador difere do internacional pelo facto de relacionar pessoas com habilidades em TIC e população total residente no país e não determinada faixa etária. O outro aspecto refere-se a fonte de dados, para este indicador a fonte de dados usada para o cálculo é administrativa e não inquérito. O calculo nao e feito por tipo de habilidade considera todas habilidades. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Balanço Anual de Actividades do Sector da CTESTP.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
